Amit Parashar

Training and Development Manager/Instructional Designer

Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India +917043428294

□ amitbparashar@gmail.com

Accomplished Training and Development professional well-versed in Instructional Design, selecting trainers, curriculum and course plans to achieve demanding training objectives. Effective at leading courses on diverse topics. Prepared to offer 14 years of progressive experience and take on challenging new role.

Functional Skills	
Training Solutions Development	ADDIE Expertise
Kirk Patrick Model Implementation	Instruction Design
Staff Development Plans and performance management	Organization Development and Change Management
Technical Skills	
Articulate 360	Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
Adobe Captivate 2019	хАРІ
SAP SuccessFactors	UX Design

Work experience

Training and Organizational Development Manager

- Assessed skill gaps for employees in various department and developed training courses to meet identified needs.
- Drove departmental performance and achievement of service levels through focused team operational reviews, structured coaching and managing to enterprise targets.
- Devised and optimized human resources processes, practices and program initiatives.
- Evaluated success of training programs and recommended improvements to upper management to enhance effectiveness.

Territory Training Manager

- Determined training needs and requirements for group by brainstorming with managers, talking with employees, or administering surveys Interact with 3 territory heads and providing (Kuwait, Qatar & Bahrain) training solutions as and when needed.
- Designed & scheduled quarterly and annual training calendars for 3 regions with reference to the Training Needs Analysis.
- Coached employees from retail, IT, buying and visual merchandising teams, on selling skills, customer services and functional modules.

Territory Concept Trainer

- Designed and implemented sales training program and documentation.
- Developed and led group training courses to align with corporate sales and service goals.
- Assessed training program effectiveness on regular basis and improved upon deficient areas.

Senior Trainer and HR Generalist

- Provided in-house training to new employees concerning maintenance of standardized training approaches.
- Effectively collaborate with business leaders to assess organizational functioning, develop improvement plans, and lead projects that support growth and drive results

Mudon Ahlia Real Estate-Kuwait

January 2019 - February 2020

Landmark Group-Kuwait, Bahrain and Qatar

December 2017 - December 2018

Landmark Group- United Arab Emirates

September 2013 - September 2017

Future Group (Future Knowledge Services/nuFuture Haribhakti Business Services)

July 2010 - January 2013

State Bank of India Credit and Payment Services Ltd.

April 2008 - July 2010

Sales Trainer

- Designed and implemented sales training program and documentation.
- Appropriately allocated resourced, budgets, inventories, training support and team building materials to increase overall productivity.

RPG Cellucom

September 2007 - April 2008

The Times of India Group

October 2005 - September 2007

Senior Store Officer

- Coordinated efficient restocking of sales floor with current merchandise and accurate signage for current promotions.
- Approached browsing customers to initiate conversations to determine buying preferences.
- Employed strategic tactics such as cross-selling and upselling to drive sales.

Senior Customer Support Executive

- Educated customers about billing, payment processing and support policies and procedures.
- Surpassed sales goals through implementation of effective marketing strategies.

Education

Chartered in Personnel Development (CIPD), London, UK

January 2020 - December 2020

ILM Qualification

October 2015 - October 2015

Advance Diploma in Professional Development in Training

March 2013 - October 2013

Master of Business Administration (MBA)

September 2009 - September 2011

DIploma in Retail Management

January 2007 - June 2007

Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA)

March 2004 - March 2008

Diploma in Learning and Development

Associate Level 5

City and Guilds, London

Certificate course in Training Skills

American TESOL Institute

Adult Learning techniques

Institute of Business Management and Research, Ahmedabad

Human Resource Management

H.L. College of Professional Education

Madhya Pradesh Bhoj University

Management studies

Certifications

- 1. Train the Trainer Program, SBI Card, August 2008
- 2. Training Excellence Certification, Landmark Group, March 2012
- 3. OSHA Safety Training: PPE Management Certificate, OSHA, December 2019
- 4. Instruction Design: Needs Analysis, LinkedIn, November 2020
- 5. Instruction Design Essentials: Models of ID, LinkedIn, November 2020
- 6. Instruction Design: Storyboarding, LinkedIn, December 2020
- 7. Instruction Design: Adult Learners, LinkedIn, December 2020
- 8. Instruction Design: Creating Video Training, LinkedIn, February 2021
- 9. E-learning essentials: Storyboarding, April 2021
- 10. Learning Articulate Storyline 3, LinkedIn, March 2021
- 11. Adobe Captivate Essential Training, LinkedIn, March 2021
- 12. Measuring Learning Effectiveness, LinkedIn, March 2021
- 13. UX Design: Overview, LinkedIn, March 2021
- 14. UX Design: Analyzing User Data, March 2021
- 15. UX Design: Creating Persona, March 2021
- 16. UX Design: Prototyping, April 2021
- 17. Google Cloud Platform (GCP) fundamentals certification (Udemy)